Curt Stern Papers 1907-1981 Mss.Ms.Coll.5
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence, 1907-1981 (Box 1-43)
  - Stern, C. Lecture - "Mutation rates", 1955; 4 items (16 pages) (Box 34)
    Cytogenetics; Genetics -- Mutation rates; Lectures, public speaking; Radiation genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Lecture - "On being a scientist", n.d.; 9 pages (Box 34)
    Lectures, public speaking; Philosophy of science; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Lecture - "One world: Genes and their action", 1948; 2 pages (Box 34)
    Drosophila genetics; Genetics; Lectures, public speaking; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Lecture - "Our changing genetic constitutions", 1967; 11 pages (Box 34)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Genetics; Human evolution, physical anthropology; Human genetics; Lectures, public speaking; Population genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Lecture - Population problems, 1962; 1 item (Box 34)
    Ethical issues; Eugenics; Genetics; Human genetics; Lectures, public speaking; Population genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Lecture - ("Population problems: Quality and quantity"), 1962; 1 item (Box 34)
  - Stern, C. Lecture - "Position effect", 1946; 3 folders (Box 34)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Genetics; Lectures, public speaking; Reviews; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Lecture - "Problems of radiobiology with emphasis on radiation genetics", 1951; 11 pages (Box 34)
  - Stern, C. Lecture - "Research and Science", 1944; 18 pages (Box 34)
    Educational matters; Lectures, public speaking; Philosophy of science; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Lecture - "Science and Religion", 1941; 10 pages (Box 34)
  - Stern, C. Lecture - "Sex-determination in plants, animals and man", 1941; 2 pages (Box 34)
    Genetics -- Animals; Genetics of plants; Human genetics; Lectures, public speaking; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Lecture - "Social implications of Human Genetics", 1969; 6 pages (Box 34)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Eugenics; Human genetics; Lectures, public speaking; Molecular genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Lectures - "Some General aspects of medical Genetics;" "Genetics of selected diseases;" and, "Current concepts in human genetics", 1960-1962; 18 pages (Box 34)
    Eugenics; Genetics; Human genetics -- Medical genetics; Lectures, public speaking; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Lecture - "Some present-day aspects of Science", 1945; 5 pages (Box 34)
  - Stern, C. Lecture - "Some problems of Human Genetics", n.d.; 2 pages (Box 34)
    Eugenics; Human genetics; Lectures, public speaking; Radiation genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Lecture - "The structure of chromosomes", 1929; 11 pages (Box 34)
    Cytogenetics; Genetics; Genetics Society (Great Britain) -- London; Lectures, public speaking; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Lecture - Student Scientific Conference, 1941; 4 pages (Box 34)
    Educational matters; Graduate study; Lectures, public speaking; Philosophy of science; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Lecture - "Survey of Human Genetics" (Baltimore, 1959; Denver, 1961), 1959-1961; 3 folders (Box 34)
    Conferences and symposia; Cytogenetics; Ecology; Eugenics; Human evolution, physical anthropology; Human genetics; Johns Hopkins University; Lectures, public speaking; Population genetics; Radiation genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, 1961; 1 item (Box 34)
    - Folder 2, 1959-1961; 1 item (Box 34)
    - Folder 3, 1959-1961; 1 item (Box 34)
  - Stern, C. Lecture - "Use of mosaics in the study of developmental effects of genes", 1966; 8 pages (Box 34)
  - Stern, C. Lecture - Wells College, 1944; 3 pages (Box 34)
    Eugenics; Genetics; History of biology, especially genetics; Lectures, public speaking -- Wells College; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Lecture - "Why do people differ?", 1946; 2 pages (Box 34)
    Educational matters; Genetics; Lectures, public speaking; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs -- Sigma Xi; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Lecture - "Young scientists, teachers, parents", 1960; 4 pages (Box 34)
    Educational matters; Lectures, public speaking; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Lectures (Box 34)
    see: Speaking engagemets.
  - Stern, C. Lectures on Pattern, n.d.; 1 item (Box 34)
  - Stern, C. Lectures - Sigma XI, 1952, 1951-1953; 16 items (Box 34)
  - Stern, C. Male sterility (notes), 1938; 3 pages (Box 34)
  - Stern, C. "Peter Medawar", 1967; 3 pages (Box 34)
    Educational matters; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Lectures, public speaking -- Medawar, Peter Brian; Philosophy of science; University of California, Berkeley; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Medical Genetics, n.d.; 10 pages (Box 34)
    Human genetics -- Medical genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. "Mendel and Human Genetics" (notes), 1965; 8 items (Box 34)
    History of biology, especially genetics; Human genetics; Mendel, Gregor; Ottensooser, Fritz; Population genetics; Population genetics -- Hardy-Weinberg law; Sturtevant, Alfred Henry; Wright, Sewall; Yule, George Udny
  - Stern, C. "Model estimates of the frequency of white and near-white segregants in the American Negro", 1952-1953; 4 folders (Box 34)
    Human genetics -- Race; Publication; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, 1953; 4 items (Box 34)
    - Folder 2, 1952-1953; 5 items (Box 34)
    - Folder 3, 1953; 1 item (Box 34)
    - Folder 4, 1952-1953; 2 items (Box 34)
  - Stern, C. "Mosaic diagrams", n.d.; 5 folders (Box 34)
    Drosophila genetics -- Research data; Publication; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, n.d.; 1 item (Box 34)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 1 item (Box 34)
    - Folder 3, n.d.; 1 item (Box 34)
    - Folder 4, n.d.; 1 item (Box 34)
    - Folder 5, n.d.; 1 item (Box 34)
  - Stern, C. "Mosaics in Drosophila" (notes), 1934; 1 folder (Box 34)
  - Stern, C. "Mosaics in Flies and Man", 1971; 5 pages (Box 34)
    Drosophila genetics; Human genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Munich (notes for paper on genetics, history?), 1972; 6 pages (Box 34)
  - Stern, C. Naples, 1929; 1 folder (Box 34)
    Biographical and personal data; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc. -- Research data
  - Stern, C. Nature-Nurture, 1958; 3 folders (Box 34)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Human genetics -- Twins; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, n.d.; 1 item (Box 34)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 1 item (Box 34)
    - Folder 3, 1958; 2 items (Box 34)
  - Stern, C. "New data on the problem of Y-linkage of hairy pinnae", 1958-1964; 8 folders (Box 35)
    Centerwall, Willard R.; Dronamraju, Krishna R.; Human genetics -- Hairy ears; Publication -- American Journal of Human Genetics; Referee's report; Reviews; Sarkar, S. S.; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, 1964; 2 items (Box 35)
    - Folder 2, 1964; 2 items (Box 35)
    - Folder 3, 1964; 1 item (Box 35)
    - Folder 4, 1964; 8 items (Box 35)
    - Folder 5, 1959-1964; 15 items (Box 35)
    - Folder 6, 1961-1964; 23 items (Box 35)
    - Folder 7, 1962-1964; 15 items (Box 35)
    - Folder 8, 1958-1964; 12 items (Box 35)
  - Stern, C. New York Times (letters to the Editor), 1945-1946; 20 items (Box 35)
    Exchange of scholars; Human evolution, physical anthropology -- Race; Human genetics; Political issues; Publication -- New York Times; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Stern, C. Newspaper clippings, 1971; 1 item (Box 35)
  - Stern, C. A note on the detection of diferential effects of mutagens", 1956-1957; 11 items (Box 35)
    Drosophila genetics; Fahmy, Myrtle J.; Fahmy, O. G.; Publication; Radiation genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Notebook on genetics, Circa 1949; 1 folder (Box 35)
  - Stern, C. Notes, 1933; 1 folder (Box 35)
    Correns, Carl; Embryology, developmental genetics; Genetics; Hammerling, Joachim; Hartmann, Max; Holtfreter, Johannes; Kaiser-Wilhelm Institutes; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Notes and figures on bristle patterns, 1 folder (Box 35)
  - Stern, C. Notes and sketches, 1923; 1 item (Box 35)
  - Stern, C. Notes and sketches, miscellaneous, Circa 1923; 2 folders (Box 35)
    - Folder 1, n.d.; 16 items (Box 35)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 8 items (Box 35)
  - Stern, C. Notes on genetics of maize [Jones], Circa 1935; 1 folder (Box 35)
    Jones, Donald F.; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Zea (maize) genetics
  - Stern, C. "On a case of lethal Ichthyosis in Hiroshima", 1957-1958; 17 items (Box 35)
    Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission -- Japan; Human genetics -- Ichthyosis; Neel, James V.; Radiation genetics; Tanaka, Katsumi; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; World War II -- Japan
  - Stern, C. On teaching vs. research at the University of California, n.d.; 8 pages (Box 35)
    Educational matters; Teaching; University of California, Berkeley; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. "On the Occurrence of Translocations and Autosomal non-disjunction in Drosophila Melanogaster", 1933-1934; 17 items (Box 35)
    Drosophila genetics; McClintock, Barbara; Publication; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. The Origin of Genetics (correspondence, 1967), 1965-1967; 16 items (Box 35)
    Dunn, Leslie Clarence; Finney, David J.; History of biology, especially genetics; Publication -- The Origin of Genetics; Reviews; Sherwood, Eva; Sturtevant, Alfred Henry; Wright, Sewall
  - Stern, C. Personality Questionnaire, n.d.; 1 folder (Box 35)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ -- Personality; Biographical and personal data; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. "Pigmentation mosaicism in intersexes of Drosophila", 1965-1979; 5 items (Box 35)
    Drosophila genetics; Embryology, developmental genetics; Publication; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. "Place of Genetics in Medicine", 1974; 19 items (Box 35)
    Human genetics; Lectures, public speaking; Publication; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Population Genetics (notes), 1944; 1 item (Box 35)
  - Stern, C. "Population Genetics" (World Population Conference, 1965), 1 folder (Box 35)
    Conferences and symposia; Human genetics; Lectures, public speaking; Population genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. "Porcupine Man", 1948-1958; 9 folders (Box 35-36)
    Boyd, Lyle Gifford; Human genetics -- Ichthyosis; Penrose, Lionel Sharples; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, 1957; 8 items (Box 35)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 5 items (Box 35)
    - Folder 3, 1956; 1 item (Box 35)
    - Folder 4, n.d.; 1 item (Box 35)
    - Folder 5, n.d.; 1 item (Box 35)
    - Folder 6, n.d.; 1 item (Box 35)
    - Folder 7, 1956-1958; 5 items (Box 35)
    - Folder 8, 1956-1957; 21 items (Box 36)
    - Folder 9, 1948-1957; 15 items (Box 36)
  - Stern, C. "Problems of y chromosome inheritance in man", 1956-1957; 2 folders (Box 36)
    Cytogenetics; Human genetics; Publication; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, 1957; 7 items (Box 36)
    - Folder 2, 1956-1957; 5 items (Box 36)
  - Stern, C. "Protozoenkurs" (Prof. Hartmann) (notes and sketches), 1921-1922; 1 folder (Box 36)
    Hartmann, Max; Protozoan genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc. -- Drawings
  - Stern, C. Public health seminar, 1960; 9 pages (Box 36)
    Conferences and symposia; Human genetics; Population genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Publications in Human Genetics, 1973; 3 pages (Box 36)
    Bibliographical matters; Human genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Radiation Genetics, 1953-1958; 7 folders (Box 36)
    Atomic Energy Commission; Drosophila genetics; Human genetics; Jones, Hardin B.; Muller, Hermann Joseph; National Academy of Sciences -- Committee on the Biological Effects of Atomic Radiation - Genetics Panel; Publication; Radiation genetics; Russell, William Lawson; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, 1958; 1 item (Box 36)
    - Folder 2, 1953-1955; 10 items (Box 36)
    - Folder 3, 1955 (ca); 2 items (Box 36)
    - Folder 4, 1957; 1 item (Box 36)
    - Folder 5, 1957 (ca); 1 item (Box 36)
    - Folder 6, 1957 (ca); 1 item (Box 36)
    - Folder 7, 1957 (ca); 1 item (Box 36)
  - Stern, C. "Ratio of monozygotic to dizygotic affected twins and the frequency of affected twins in unselected data", 1958; 3 folders (Box 36)
    Cytogenetics; Embryology, developmental genetics; Human genetics -- Twins; Publication; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, 1958; 1 item (Box 36)
    - Folder 2, 1958; 1 item (Box 36)
    - Folder 3, 1958; 1 item (Box 36)
  - Stern, C. "Reflections on Armistice Day, 1940", 1 folder (Box 36)
    Political issues; University of Rochester; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; World War I -- Impact on science; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Stern, C. "Religious questionings" (Rochester), 1939; 6 pages (Box 36)
    Ethical issues; Philosophy of science; University of Rochester; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Report on activities during tenure of a Miller Research Professorship, 1961-1962; 4 items (Box 36)
    Biographical and personal data; Drosophila genetics; Embryology, developmental genetics; University of California, Berkeley -- Miller Research Professorship; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Report on foreign travel, 1965; 1 folder (Box 36)
    Biographical and personal data; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; University of California, Berkeley; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Research grant (N.S.F), 1972; 2 items (Box 36)
  - Stern, C. Research grant proposals (N.I.H.) "Mosaicism and developmental genetics in Drosophila", 1970; 3 items (Box 36)
    Drosophila genetics; Embryology, developmental genetics; National Institutes of Health; Research support; Tokunaga, Chiyoko
  - Stern, C. Research grants, 1958-1970; 2 folders (Box 36)
    Bibliographical matters; Research support; University of California, Berkeley; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, 1958-1959; 4 items (Box 36)
    - Folder 2, 1969-1970; 8 items (Box 36)
  - Stern, C. Research notes and calculations, 4 folders (Box 36)
    - Folder 1, n.d.; 1 item (Box 36)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 1 item (Box 36)
    - Folder 3, n.d.; 1 item (Box 36)
    - Folder 4, n.d.; 1 item (Box 36)
  - Stern, C. Retirement and birthday greetings, 1970; 1 folder (Box 36)
    Biographical and personal data; Congratulations, greetings, thanks
  - Stern, C. Reviews (by Stern), 1932-1944; 3 items (Box 36)
    Genetics; Reviews
  - Stern, C. Reviews - The Origin of Genetics, 1967 (ca); 5 items (Box 36)
  - Stern, C. Reviews - "Selection and Eugenics", 1949; 6 items (Box 36)
    Caspari, Ernst Wilhelm; Eugenics; Goodale, Hubert Dana; Human genetics; Reviews
  - Stern, C. "Rhizopoda", 1920-1930; 1 folder (Box 36)
    Protozoan genetics -- Rhizopoda; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc. -- Drawings
  - Stern, C. Sabbatical reports, 1951-1968; 11 items (Box 36)
    Research support; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; University of California, Berkeley; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. San Francisco Chronicle (letters to the editor), 1955-1969; 2 items (Box 36)
  - Stern, C. "Selection, polymorphism" (notes), 1969; 7 pages (Box 36)
  - Stern, C. "Self-introduction" (Amererican Society of Zoologists), 1962; 1 folder (Box 36)
    Biographical and personal data -- Humor; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs -- American Society of Zoologists; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. "Sensory physiology of the relations between honey bees and flowers", 1942; 2 items (8 pages) (Box 36)
    Frisch, Karl von; Genetics; Lectures, public speaking; Physiology; University of Rochester; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Sigma Xi lecture tour, 1953 - Journal, 1952-1953; 1 item (Box 36)
    Biographical and personal data; Business; Drosophila genetics; Lectures, public speaking -- Sigma Xi; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. "Somatic recombination within the white locus of Drosophila Melanogaster", 1968-1969; 2 folders (Box 36)
    Bibliographical matters; Chovnick, Arthur; Drosophila genetics; Judd, Burke H.; LeFever, H. Michael; Li, Ching Chun; Publication; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Welshons, William
    - Folder 1, 1968-1969; 14 items (Box 36)
    - Folder 2, 1969; 1 item (Box 36)
  - Stern, C. "Some general problems of human inheritance" (notes), 1939; 3 pages (Box 36)
    Human genetics; Lectures, public speaking; University of Rochester; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Speaking engagements (letters, announcements, notes, etc.), 1959-1970; 5 folders (Box 37)
    Graduate study; Lectures, public speaking; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, 1959-1960; 17 items (Box 37)
    - Folder 2, 1961-1962; 13 items (Box 37)
    - Folder 3, 1962-1964; 15 items (Box 37)
    - Folder 4, 1962-1965; 13 items (Box 37)
    - Folder 5, 1966-1970; 19 items (Box 37)
  - Stern, C. "A. H. Sturtevant", Circa 1970; 1 folder (Box 37)
    Biographical and personal data -- Sturtevant, Alfred Henry; Bridges, Calvin B.; Cytogenetics; Dobzhansky, Theodosius; Drosophila genetics; Embryology, developmental genetics; Evolution; Lectures, public speaking -- Eulogy; Population genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. "Summary of position effect tests of various translocations", 1942; 1 folder (Box 37)
  - Stern, C. Symposium - Cold Spring Harbor, 1938; 1 item (Box 37)
  - Stern, C. Symposium - "Genetic and environmental determinants of intelligence", 1969; 6 items (Box 37)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Conferences and symposia; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Symposium - "Man and the atomic age", 1949; 3 items (Box 37)
    Conferences and symposia; University of California, San Francisco; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. Testis shapes and colors of Drosophila species, 3 folders (Box 37)
    Drosophila genetics; Photographs; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, n.d.; 1 item (Box 37)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 1 item (Box 37)
    - Folder 3, n.d.; 1 item (Box 37)
  - Stern, C. "Über Wechselbeziehungen zwischen allgemeiner Genetik und Humangenetik", 9 pages (Box 37)
  - Stern, C. "Unforgettable Kindness", 1971; 2 pages (Box 37)
    Biographical and personal data; Ethical issues; Lectures, public speaking; Publication; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; World War I
  - Stern, C. U.S.S.R. Exchange Visit, 1963; 2 folders (Box 37)
    Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Lectures, public speaking; National Academy of Sciences; Porter, Keith R.; Russian politics and science; Russian politics and science -- Lysenko, Trofim Denisovich; Stent, Gunther S.; Travel -- U.S.S.R.; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, 1963; 12 items (Box 37)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 3 items (Box 37)
  - Stern, C. U.S.S.R. Exchange Visit - Diary May 13 - June 2, 1963, 1 item (Box 37)
    Russian politics and science
  - Stern, C. U.S.S.R. Exchange Visit - "A geneticist's visit to Russia", 1963; 1 item (Box 37)
    Russian politics and science; Travel -- U.S.S.R.
  - Stern, C. U.S.S.R. Exchange Visit, 1963 - Reports, 1 item (Box 37)
  - Stern, C. University of California, Berkeley. Bio-Bibliography, 1961-1973; 4 folders (Box 37)
    Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Honors; Lectures, public speaking; Research support; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Teaching; University of California, Berkeley
    - Folder 1, 1961; 1 item (Box 37)
    - Folder 2, 1962; 1 item (Box 37)
    - Folder 3, 1968; 1 item (Box 37)
    - Folder 4, 1973; 1 item (Box 37)
  - Stern, C. University of California, Berkeley. Faculty Research Lecture, 1964; 1 item (Box 37)
    Congratulations, greetings, thanks; Honors; Lectures, public speaking; Philosophy of science; Research support; Teaching; University of California, Berkeley
  - Stern, C. University of California, Berkeley. Faculty Research Lecturer, 1963-1964; 12 items (Box 37)
    Educational matters; Lectures, public speaking; University of California, Berkeley
  - Stern, C. University of California, Berkeley. Remarks at Commencement of the Zoology and General Biology Departments, 1970; 1 item (Box 37)
  - Stern, C. University of California, Berkeley. Zoology 151 address, 1970; 1 folder (Box 37)
    Educational matters; Human genetics; Political issues; University of California, Berkeley; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Zoology
  - Stern, C. University of California, Berkeley. Zoology 253, 1968; 1 folder (Box 37)
    Bibliographical matters; Educational matters; Genetics; University of California, Berkeley; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc. -- Seminar reports; Zoology
  - Stern, C. University of Rochester, Department of Zoology, 1935; 1 item (Box 37)
    University of Rochester; Zoology
  - Stern, C. University of Rochester. "The News about the University of Rochester", 1944; 1 item (Box 37)
    University of Rochester; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Stern, C. University of Rochester. Notes for farewell dinner, 1947, 1970; 1 item (Box 37)
    Biographical and personal data; University of Rochester
  - Stern, C. University of Rochester, Office of the Extension Division. Notice of Appointment 1937, 1987; 1 item (Box 37)
    University of Rochester
  - Stern, C. University of Rochester. Salary, 1935; 1 item (Box 37)
  - Stern, C. "Untersuchungen uber Acanthocystideen", 1924; 2 folders (Box 37)
    Publication; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Zoology
    - Folder 1, n.d.; 1 item (Box 37)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 1 item (Box 37)
  - Stern, C. "Whom will our child resemble?", n.d.; 8 pages (Box 37)
  - Stern, C. Wing correlation, n.d.; 7 folders (Box 37)
    Drosophila genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc. -- Drawings; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc. -- Research data
    - Folder 1, n.d.; 1 item (Box 37)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 1 item (Box 37)
    - Folder 3, n.d.; 1 item (Box 37)
    - Folder 4, n.d.; 1 item (Box 37)
    - Folder 5, n.d.; 1 item (Box 37)
    - Folder 6, n.d.; 1 item (Box 37)
    - Folder 7, n.d.; 1 item (Box 37)
  - Stern, C. "Wilhelm Weinberg" 1962, 1956-1973; 4 folders (Box 37)
    Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data -- Weinberg, Wilhelm; Dunn, Leslie Clarence; Eugenics; Human genetics; Human genetics -- Twins; Population genetics -- Hardy-Weinberg law; Publication; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Verschuer, Otmar, Freiherr von
    - Folder 1, 1962-1973; 6 items (Box 37)
    - Folder 2, 1961-1962; 1 item (Box 37)
    - Folder 3, 1962; 5 items (Box 37)
    - Folder 4, 1956-1961; 14 items (Box 37)
  - Stern, C. "Zur Histologie und Regeneration der ungeschlechtlichen Fortpflanzung bei Stenostomum", 1 folder (Box 38)
    Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Zoology
  - Stern, C. and Gertrud Belar. "Race crossing in paradise" 1954, 1948-1955; 23 items (Box 38)
    Anthropology -- Cultural anthropology; Art; Human genetics -- Race; Photographs; Publication; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. and Calvin B. Bridges. "The mutants of the extreme left end of the second chromosome of Drosophila melanogaster", 1926; 4 folders (Box 38)
    - Folder 1, 1926; 1 item (Box 38)